# VIDUL TYAGI

New Delhi, India | P: +91 9872399779 | vidultyagi18@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/vidultyagi995/

### PERSONAL SUMMARY

Developer with nearly 4.5 years of experience in end-to-end frontend technology transformation projects, including design reviews, business requirements understanding and implementation, agile implementations & code testing. Strong professional background with experience in banking domain and telecommunication domain. Advocating the idea of implementing best code practices and follow all necessary guidelines of AGILE.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# AMDOCS - Gurugram, India

### Advanced Software Developer

October 2021 - Present

- Client TRUE Thailand.
- Developing a website which consists of all the types of services provided by TRUE to its consumers. Handling billing, credit limits, accounts, subscribers etc. for individual under one 360 Dashboard which is developed for customer accessibility.
- Code base: Working on HARMONY framework using ReactJS, TYPESCRIPT, REDUX as frontend technologies
- Other tools used: INVISION, AXURE Wireframe, Confluence, JIRA, DRAW.IO, ALM OCTANE, HP ALM (Application Lifecycle Management).
- Role: Senior Developer in the team who takes higher responsibilities of code review and delivering quality code. Advocating to
  promote AGILE practices in a tight timeline. Team player who leads by example and strives for growth.

### **INFOSYS - Pune, India**

# Senior Systems Engineer

March 2021 - October 2021

- Client Westpac, one of Australia's Big Four banks, and Australia's first and oldest banking institution.
- Managing a 3-member team in Credit Risk Assessment module, designed with the aim to provide a hassle-free experience to businesses for applying a loan. The user obtains a conditional approval for the loan by providing certain financial details like proposal, sponsorship, business history etc. to make a strong profile based on which their loan application will be reviewed.
- Code base: Working on WESTPAC framework using ReactJS, JAVASCRIPT, REDUX, JEST, NODEJs as frontend technologies
- Other tools used: Confluence, JIRA, HP ALM (Application Lifecycle Management).
- Role: Senior Developer in the team who manages 3 people and delivers high quality code and reviews code. Team player who
  leads by example and strives for growth.

# Systems Engineer

April 2018 - February 2021

- Client Westpac, one of Australia's Big Four banks, and Australia's first and oldest banking institution.
- Working in modules Business Division Mortgages and Consumer Property Lending designed with the aim to display the
  assessments for users who have applied for loan and capturing details for personal and business assets or facilities, according
  to which loan is given. Reports are made once the application is completed.
- Code base: Working on WESTPAC framework using ReactJS, JAVASCRIPT, REDUX, JEST, NODEJs as frontend technologies
- Other tools used: Confluence, JIRA, HP ALM (Application Lifecycle Management).
- Role: Developer learning new technologies. Working with a large team and small team in different modules. Considered for
   Onsite opportunity in Australia just after 4 months of getting into the project. I displayed a dynamic personality and a positive
   attitude.

### **INTERNSHIP**

# KHANNA PAPER MILLS - Amritsar, India

#### •

Jan 2016 - June 2016

 Designed solutions for expansion of paper unit and improved overall efficiency of paper production by 9% by running automating systems.

# **EDUCATION**

### THAPAR UNIVERSITY - Patiala, India

August 2013 - June 2017

Bachelor of Engineering, Mechatronics Engineering

# **Certifications & Training**

CORE JAVA training in Amritsar from NIIT.

Languages: Native in Hindi; Fluent in English and Punjabi.

Interests: Football, Cycling, Movies, Sports, Dance